# **BRAD BROGE**

#### Durham, NC 27703

https://www.linkedin.com/in/brbroge/ https://github.com/b-r-broge

brbroge@gmail.com

763.226.1513

#### SUMMARY

## Providing full-stack solutions for the complete software cycle

Motivated professional with experience in complete software life-cycle; requirements analysis, design, object-oriented development, and client support. Capable of troubleshooting complex JavaScript, Python, hardware, or operating system problems. Approachable, hardworking and capable of synthesizing complex ideas into consumable information for technical and non-technical persons. Comfortable in a fast paced, Agile environment, and excels where deep team work and dedication to finding a solution is key.

JavaScript Language & Frameworks | Full-stack Design & Optimization Web Development | Client Driven Solutions | Linux

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | React | NodeJs | Linux | Git | Shell | SQL | Python | GitHub | Agile

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IBM, Rochester, MN / Durham, NC

2011 - 2017

**Staff Software Engineer** *IBM Cloud Automation Manager* 

2016 - 2017

Worked to develop exciting new cross-cloud deployment solution using NodeJS, Strongloop and other technologies to integrate and automate the process of connecting to various public clouds, deployed templates and monitored results.

- Created new APIs, enhancing core product features.
- Acquired skills in JavaScript and NodeJS, improving development.
- Updated existing JavaScript, adding functionality and stability.
- Explored new technologies and implementations, identifying possible product expansions.

#### **Staff Software Engineer**

2015 - 2016

IBM PureApplication System - Centralized Pattern Development
Produced new patterns to run on IBM PureApplication platform. Automated collection of
system data to properly install and configure IBM middleware with minimal effort from the
end user. Worked with clients to get and set expectations for function and features the
pattern would include.

- Scripted in Python and Shell, gathering unique VM information, permitting automated middleware installation, greatly reducing complexity, installation, and configuration times for middleware products.
- Created customer desired patterns, allowing for the closing of high value deals.

- Analyzed complex middleware architectures, implementing common customer use cases.
- Gathered customer requirements and feedback during development cycle, executing feature requests to fit customer needs.

**Staff Software Engineer** *IBM PureApplication System – SWAT Team* 2012 – 2015 Provided direct support to manufacturing and customer to build, install and maintain IBM PureApplication Systems including installation and configuration of custom software. Validated healthy IPAS and network configurations and ran upgrades on active customer systems.

- Performed installation and upgrades to client systems, including those in production, at client sites around the globe, ensuring customer system stability and health.
- Responded to system down events and delivered local support, confirming complete resolution of customer problems.
- Delivered support to manufacturing for building and shipping IBM PureApplication Systems, allowing for on time delivery.
- Led transition effort, moving IBM PureApplication Manufacturing from Rochester, Minnesota to Guadalajara, Mexico, hastening the transition by an entire quarter.

**Software Engineer** *IBM WebSphere Application Server - CTS Team* 2011 - 2012 Ran business critical Continuous Test Support to ensure the latest versions of WebSphere Application Server was fully certifiable as J2EE compliant for Java 6 and Java 7.

- Executed and analyzed test results, verifying full compliance with Java technologies.
- Updated testing scripts to work on different types of hardware, ensuring cross-platform support.

## **CONTINUED EDUCATION**

The Iron Yard, Durham, NC

### **Web Development Career Path**

2017 - 2017

Entered a full time technical boot camp for 3 months designed to give a broad understanding of web development from both a front-end and back-end perspective. Learning is focused on the most recent technologies in ES6, and utilizes hands on project based development practice.

- Developed a fully functional front end application utilizing VueJS framework.
- Further deepened JavaScript and NodeJS skills to increase understanding of configuring API end points, and Database connections using ORMs.
- Created multiple Single-Page Applications in React, developing a deep understanding of React architecture.
- Worked in teams to develop complex Single-Page Applications in React using Redux.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Arts (BA)**, Computer Science, Luther College, Decorah, IA **Bachelor of Arts (BA)**, Mathematics, Luther College, Decorah, IA